export const chapter = "Chapter - 12: Forests: Our Lifeline";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      [
        {
          question:
            "What is the upper, extensively branched part of a tree that is often a characteristic of any particular species?",
          optionA: "Canopy",
          optionB: "Crown",
          optionC: "Understorey",
          correctAnswer: "b",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Which layer of the forest receives plenty of sunlight and is home to animals like hornbills, butterflies, and bats?",
          optionA: "Canopy Layer",
          optionB: "Understorey Layer",
          optionC: "Emergent Layer",
          correctAnswer: "c",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What is the primary function of the Canopy Layer in a forest?",
          optionA: "Block sunlight",
          optionB: "Provide habitat for animals like eagles and toucans",
          optionC: "Act as a wind breaker",
          correctAnswer: "b",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Which layer of the forest is hot, damp, and home to animals like owls, lizards, and jaguars?",
          optionA: "Forest Floor",
          optionB: "Canopy Layer",
          optionC: "Understorey Layer",
          correctAnswer: "c",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What percentage of sunlight does the Forest Floor receive?",
          optionA: "5%",
          optionB: "2%",
          optionC: "10%",
          correctAnswer: "b",
        },
        {
          question: "What is the role of forests in reducing noise pollution?",
          optionA: "Regulatory",
          optionB: "Accessory",
          optionC: "Protective",
          correctAnswer: "c",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What is the term for the transfer of energy through a series of organisms, each feeding on the preceding organism, in a forest ecosystem?",
          optionA: "Food web",
          optionB: "Food chain",
          optionC: "Energy cycle",
          correctAnswer: "b",
        },
        {
          question: "Why are forests referred to as the 'lungs of the earth'?",
          optionA: "They produce oxygen during photosynthesis",
          optionB: "They absorb carbon dioxide",
          optionC: "They provide shelter to animals",
          correctAnswer: "a",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What is the term for the cutting down of forests around the world?",
          optionA: "Afforestation",
          optionB: "Deforestation",
          optionC: "Forestation",
          correctAnswer: "b",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What is the recommended alternative to cutting down trees for cooking, according to the text?",
          optionA: "Use of fire breakers",
          optionB: "Social forestry programme",
          optionC: "Use of clean fuels like biogas",
          correctAnswer: "c",
        },
      ],
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blanks:",
    questions: [
      [
        {
          question:
            "The _________ layer is formed by the emerging part of the taller trees, reaching a height up to 200 feet. This layer receives plenty of sunlight.",
          optionA: "Canopy",
          optionB: "Understorey",
          optionC: "Emergent",
          correctAnswer: "Emergent",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The tips of the leaves in the Canopy Layer are called _________, as they let rainwater run down and keep them dry.",
          optionA: "Drip tips",
          optionB: "Crown tips",
          optionC: "Canopy tips",
          correctAnswer: "Drip tips",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The Understorey Layer is hot and damp, home to animals like owls, lizards, and jaguars, and receives very little _________.",
          optionA: "Rainfall",
          optionB: "Sunshine",
          optionC: "Wind",
          correctAnswer: "Sunshine",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The bottom layer of a forest, the Forest Floor, receives only _________ percent of sunlight, making it dark and wet.",
          optionA: "5%",
          optionB: "2%",
          optionC: "10%",
          correctAnswer: "2%",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Forests are often referred to as the 'lungs of the earth' because they produce oxygen during the process of _________.",
          optionA: "Respiration",
          optionB: "Photosynthesis",
          optionC: "Transpiration",
          correctAnswer: "Photosynthesis",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The process of breaking down dead and decaying matter by decomposers in a forest helps in the formation of dark-colored organic matter called _________.",
          optionA: "Humus",
          optionB: "Mulch",
          optionC: "Peat",
          correctAnswer: "Humus",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Deforestation leads to the disturbance of the _________ cycle, affecting the release of water vapors into the atmosphere.",
          optionA: "Oxygen",
          optionB: "Nitrogen",
          optionC: "Water",
          correctAnswer: "Water",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Forests act as windbreakers, reducing the speed of wind and helping in the prevention of _________ away of topsoil.",
          optionA: "Blowing",
          optionB: "Erosion",
          optionC: "Evaporation",
          correctAnswer: "Erosion",
        },
        {
          question:
            "_______ are considered as nature laboratories that have contributed to the study and research in various branches of natural science.",
          optionA: "Forests",
          optionB: "Canopies",
          optionC: "Emergents",
          correctAnswer: "Forests",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Conservation of forests involves the continuous undertaking of _________ programs to preserve the balance in nature.",
          optionA: "Afforestation",
          optionB: "Deforestation",
          optionC: "Reforestation",
          correctAnswer: "Afforestation",
        },
      ],
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      [
        {
          question:
            "Forests consist of distinct horizontal layers: Emergent, Canopy, Understorey, and Forest Floor.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The Canopy Layer, being the uppermost level of a forest, is crowded and blocks out most of the sunlight.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The Forest Floor receives about 10% of sunlight, making it warm, damp, and shady.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Forests play a role in reducing noise pollution by acting as windbreakers.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The transfer of energy through a series of organisms, each feeding on the preceding organism, is known as a food web.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Deforestation does not affect the water cycle, as it is a natural process.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Forests act as the 'lungs of the earth' by releasing carbon dioxide during photosynthesis.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The Maratha Empire declared itself an empire in 1701 under the leadership of Chhatrapati Shivaji.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The Peshwas set up their capital at Delhi, concentrating powers in their hands.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The Jats established an independent state of Bharatpur under the command of Churaman.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
      ],
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
